<archimate:ArchimateDiagramModel
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Zoning model"
    id="id-f8de35153186411db77cf34fe61fbeba">
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-e400a93827794dafa225a6535d79262b">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="338"
        y="225"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-b0227fd63d86473fa09c8940ef850180.xml#id-b0227fd63d86473fa09c8940ef850180"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-62a81cb414514d03b7e224bd8c62ebeb">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="480"
        y="225"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-ff2415fad8794bc8a73c1da363c76e40.xml#id-ff2415fad8794bc8a73c1da363c76e40"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-6c55b04a4185432f8ea45788c5638cf0">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="624"
        y="225"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-ace1ea2f04a348e9a87b53971289b9af.xml#id-ace1ea2f04a348e9a87b53971289b9af"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-b87864d8dab04e2c842518e7178445d9">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="768"
        y="225"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-41180f0a440f4e3e99ceb41baae8e94f.xml#id-41180f0a440f4e3e99ceb41baae8e94f"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-35daa5b45b484ec5bb52a5a562452051">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="480"
        y="300"
        width="408"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-f2482a5e04ef4f288a344d1813127ca5.xml#id-f2482a5e04ef4f288a344d1813127ca5"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-c6b34294ded34f82af47d9d3fff97044">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="480"
        y="384"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-f6dc4f53c7f94fd7a024562fa3d853b2.xml#id-f6dc4f53c7f94fd7a024562fa3d853b2"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-c0d353f2acd54f08a5ab6cd6ab96a119">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="624"
        y="384"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-032d7845026b49c0bec57ccef9a9be39.xml#id-032d7845026b49c0bec57ccef9a9be39"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-85c2efe3227546f0b074608756af6db3">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="768"
        y="384"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-4e800022ef7f4355a0ee7ff7d274d01f.xml#id-4e800022ef7f4355a0ee7ff7d274d01f"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-4054b69a0bbe470395895bb0caa41699">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="1016"
        y="225"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-e4e73555f2f94249baf411f273e9d796.xml#id-e4e73555f2f94249baf411f273e9d796"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-fbaeda54ba684518b75ffa470687e704">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="1016"
        y="300"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-d6c9345d4ac1493da869eee833374bf2.xml#id-d6c9345d4ac1493da869eee833374bf2"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelNote"
      id="id-8c7c01f21d8d4886956629c92164e5c1"
      textAlignment="1"
      content="Based on https://www.noraonline.nl/wiki/Beschouwingsmodel_zonering#&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;External:&#xA;This domain encompasses everything that falls outside the direct protection and management of an organization and should therefore be considered untrusted. Various communication channels to the external world can be established from within an organization: connections to an untrusted zone, a semi-trusted zone, a trusted zone, and a highly trusted zone. For example, if an organization's IT management is entirely outsourced, a highly trusted channel is required to the management service provider. This channel is also needed for exchanging highly confidential information between organizations. Organizations that fully trust each other implement mutual measures and maintain security levels to ensure that only limited border protection is needed at the connection point. Organizations that exchange information at a semi-trusted level also take these measures, requiring limited border protection.&#xA;In summary, the strictness of measures for connecting to untrusted zones mainly focuses on border protection in the communication channel. When connecting trusted zones, the emphasis is primarily on protective measures within the channel itself (the strength of the tunnel).&#xA;&#xA;DMZ (Demilitarized Zone):&#xA;This domain is a neutral area between the external world and the organization, primarily serving as a relay. The external side of a DMZ is formed by border protection with strong filtering functions. Within the DMZ, mechanisms exist for protocol filtering and blocking unwanted communications, as well as functionalities for decoupling (proxies), protocol transformation, hacker deception, and monitoring.&#xA;In many cases, the DMZ also contains web servers that hold publicly accessible organizational data. The security level is semi-trusted because the data in a DMZ must, in the worst case, be considered disposable. If the external border protection is breached, a hacker could gain access to the data within the DMZ. The filtering mechanisms and the border protection between the DMZ and the organization must prevent hackers from progressing from the DMZ to trusted domains.&#xA;&#xA;Front Office:&#xA;The front office of an organization is a trusted zone. It contains systems oriented towards the external world, such as web servers. The front office includes both informational web servers and web servers that facilitate user transactions to the back office. From the customer's perspective, the front office functions as a &quot;gateway,&quot; where customer information is processed into organizational information and vice versa. The interface between the front and back office operates as a network or a &quot;service bus&quot; where back-office information is made available. The front office is classified as a trusted domain.&#xA;&#xA;Back Office:&#xA;This zone contains both supporting systems for the front office and systems used to populate business-critical systems located in the data zone. The back office is a trusted domain where applications essential for the organization's normal business operations run.&#xA;&#xA;Vault:&#xA;This zone contains only business information that is crucial for the survival of the organization—these are the &quot;crown jewels&quot; of the organization. Communication with this zone is limited to a select number of systems from the trusted zone, and data exchange is controlled.&#xA;&#xA;Client:&#xA;This zone encompasses the office environment, including end-user workstation equipment, LAN networks, and network printers within an organization. This end-user system environment is referred to as the &quot;client.&quot; This domain is classified as semi-trusted due to the large number of connections and its relatively high vulnerability to breaches. Security policy compliance in this &quot;office domain&quot; is typically limited. If organizations allow employees to work within an office environment using systems in the development, test, acceptance, or management zones, additional measures must be implemented to ensure the required logical separation and segregation of duties for security levels. These measures include both technical and organizational controls.&#xA;&#xA;Portable Media:&#xA;Client devices, depending on their type, are equipped with DVD/CD-ROM drives, memory slots, USB interfaces, and wireless network interfaces such as Wi-Fi and Bluetooth. This domain is considered untrusted because, with the exception of encrypted USB sticks issued by the organization, these devices do not fall under the organization's management. To prevent malicious code from entering the client environment via these media, policy rules dictate that these interfaces are either restricted or disabled, and all data transferred between clients and portable media is inspected.&#xA;&#xA;Management:&#xA;This zone is highly trusted, as administrators with elevated privileges must be able to perform their tasks securely. Access to administrative clients is segregated from regular office tasks, which can be performed from internal client systems. Through role separation and technical measures, administrative tasks are strictly isolated from auditing activities. Management functions performed via remote management clients or internal clients have restricted privileges compared to those available within the organization’s management zone.&#xA;&#xA;Audit:&#xA;This zone is used to separate monitoring and verification functions from operational management tasks. Audit information from log files must not be modified or altered unnoticed by administrators or end users. Audit-related information is aggregated and securely stored in the audit zone, and it does not leave this zone in its original form via the network.&#xA;&#xA;Experimental Environment:&#xA;This zone is a laboratory environment that is physically separated from other environments. Due to the experimental nature of IT resources and work processes within this environment (also referred to as a laboratory), this is classified as an untrusted domain.&#xA;&#xA;Development Environment:&#xA;In this zone, new products are developed and tested, or systems are isolated pending approval for deployment in the organization's production environment. The development domain is classified as semi-trusted, as it requires the use of utilities and tools that are either restricted or not permitted in production environments.&#xA;&#xA;Test Environment:&#xA;In this zone, systems undergo functional and technical testing to ensure they meet the required specifications. The trust level of this domain is determined by the necessary isolated setup and the restriction that no production data may be processed or stored in this zone.&#xA;&#xA;Acceptance Environment:&#xA;This domain serves as the &quot;gateway&quot; to the production environment. Here, systems are certified to meet production environment requirements. The trust level is also semi-trusted because no production data may be stored here. The acceptance environment follows similar security measures as the production environment to simulate a realistic business situation.">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="300"
        y="468"
        width="889"
        height="1105"/>
  </children>
  <children
      xsi:type="archimate:DiagramModelArchimateObject"
      id="id-e5820b1e2a084b86948a59bb5d101cd9"
      fillColor="#ff8080">
    <features
        name="deriveElementLineColor"
        value="false"/>
    <bounds
        x="132"
        y="225"
        width="120"
        height="64"/>
    <archimateElement
        xsi:type="archimate:CommunicationNetwork"
        href="CommunicationNetwork_id-138d3675b6f541f1aa777d5ec63ea583.xml#id-138d3675b6f541f1aa777d5ec63ea583"/>
  </children>
</archimate:ArchimateDiagramModel>
